317-750-2570

# .Net Developer

Proven experience with problem identification and solving by utilizing critical thinking. Hard working habits and capability of enduring long hours. Practical thinking and technical skills accompanied by skill in using my hands.

Knowledge and experience with hardware systems. Experienced and completed a .NET Bootcamp at the Eleven Fifty Academy. Participated in group projects and took on leadership roles while helping others grow alongside myself. Capable of conducting personal research and presenting results and projects in a professional manner. Willing to learn through failing and determination.

- Experience with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, SQL
- Knowledge in ASP.Net Web Applications, MVC 5, Entity Framework, SQL Server, MYSQL
- Utilization of GIT, Drop Box, GITHub, BitBucket, Slack, Jira, Confluence
- Certified as a Microsoft TA for software development
- Capable of front-end and back-end work
- Familiarity with Mac and PC environments
- Great at critical thinking and analytical problem solving
- Excels at public speaking and soft skills
- Trained to utilize Scrum and Agile Methodologies
- Understand when to lead and when to follow

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Eleven Fifty Academy Carmel, IN

.Net APPrentice May 2016-Current

The Eleven Fifty Academy works with developers and innovators in the coding industry to skill up and introduce people to programming.

- .Net Student for 9 intense weeks
- Earned a Software Developer Microsoft Technology Associate Certification.

- Utilized Git and source control
- Worked with various team members and team sizes
- Soft skills classes
- Worked in front end and back end development scenarios

### John Force Racing Brownsburg, IN

Facility Maintenance Oct 2012-Feb 2014, Hospitality Associate Feb 2014-Dec 2014, Mechanic/Crew Member Dec 2014-Mar 2016

John Force Racing has the most wins and is the most successful name in NHRA Drag Racing. JFR has four different race teams in the two fastest and most competitive categories: Funny Cars and Top Fuel Dragsters.

- Started in facility maintenance at the Brownsburg shop.
- Did anything from running errands to cleaning to fixing things in the shop.
- My tenacity earned me a position traveling and setting up hospitality display and interacting with fans.
- Requested to work on a race team, was approved and started on Robert Hight's Funny Car team.
- Responsible for all tires: mounting, sizing and stretching, balancing.
- Maintained and repaired body: carbon fiber work on any cracks and breaks.
- Traveled extensively throughout entire United States

### Lowe's Home Improvement Store Brownsburg, IN

Cashier Oct 2010-Mar 2011, Indoor Lawn and Garden Sales Associate Mar 2011-Aug 2011, Millwork Sales Associate Aug 2011-Oct 2012

- Front End support as a cashier.
- My initiative earned me a position in the Indoor Lawn and Garden department.
- Gained experience with numerous store systems and procedures.
- Desired a more diverse store experience and was approved to move to Millwork.
- Experienced custom and special order sales as well as arranging various installation projects.

### Pavilion Cinemas Brownsburg, IN

Cashier and Custodian Oct 2009- Oct 2010

- Cashier in both Box Office and Concessions positions
- Prepared all concessions
- Cleaned, maintained, and prepared all theaters between show times

### **EDUCATION**

### Eleven Fifty Academy Carmel, IN

Computer Programming Foundations and .Net Accelerated Learning Program

# Purdue University, School of Engineering at IUPUI Indianapolis, IN

Mechanical Engineering Technology, 8/2011 – 5/2012

### Brownsburg High School, Brownsburg, IN

Emphasis on Project Lead the Way Engineering curriculum, May, 2011

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

### **Eleven Fifty Academy:**

March 2016-May2016

The Eleven Fifty Academy has gained a reputation for being able to skill up current developers and producing new developers in a very intense, quick and highly valuable way. I was one of the students to take part in the maiden voyage of their 9 week, .Net Accelerated Learning Program. After having excelled throughout the course, I was given the opportunity to become an APPrentice with the Academy, to sharpen and hone my skills in .Net development.

### **Funny Cars Team Wins:**

August 2015, Brainerd, Minnesota

The Funny Car field had become very competitive early in the season. Our team was, unfortunately, playing catch up. We adapted our own solution by utilizing more thrust from the headers and turned things around and won our first race in over a year. It was my personal first win ever.

October 2015, Las Vegas, Nevada

There had been five races since our last win in Brainerd. We had lost in the first round of every race except for one. We had been changing things on the car that had not been working so we went back to what we knew would work. We bounced back quickly and won the race.

### Senior Project in Engineering Design & Development Cadre Class

Brownsburg High School, August 2010-May 2011

This was a course only for seniors who had taken previous Gateways to Technology/Project Lead the Way courses. The class took place throughout the whole year and culminated my 6 years of previous GTT/PLTW classes. I was faced with the challenge of researching a common problem and devising a practical solution. Throughout the project, I made use of various consultants in the community, used Autodesk Inventor which is a CAD program to design my device, and utilized an engineer's notebook to record and document everything about the project. I also made a 20 minute presentation of my solution to committee of people from the community. I received recognition for Best Presentation and Best Q&A Session from my instructor and the committee.

## SuperMileage Car competition, Project Lead the Way Club

Brownsburg High School, October 2009-April 2010

The SuperMileage Car is a sponsored competition to promote engineering and technology in high schools. 2009 was the first time BHS had participated in the competition. We had to design a single-person vehicle that utilized aerodynamic design to get the highest gas mileage, all from scratch. I served as the leader of the 15 students that made up the team. We researched, designed and built our car over 1500-1600 man hours. We had help from a friend to weld the aluminum frame but we fabricated everything else. The car achieved 267 miles per gallon and we finished eleventh overall and first among rookies.